# Shreyas Vedpathak

04 Jan 2001 | shreyasvedpathak@gmail.com | 9881898291 | Pune, India

LinkedIn ID: shreyasvedpathak | Github ID: shreyasvedpathak | Website: shreyasvedpathak.github.io

Stackoverflow: shreyasvedpathak

#### **PROFILE**

1+ years of expertise building and implementing deep learning algorithms using TensorFlow and PyTorch. Excited about increasing studies into artificial intelligence. I have solid technical expertise as well as an academic background in Engineering, Statistics, and Machine Learning.

#### **EDUCATION**

2018 – present Pune, India MIT World Peace University 2

Bachelor of Technology

Branch: Computer Science and Technology

Current CGPA: 9.47

#### **SKILLS**

C • C++ • Python • Tensorflow • PyTorch • Scikit Learn • MySQL • MongoDB • Tableau

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Nov 2021 – present Ahmedabad, India

#### **Computer Vision Intern**

*Upjao Agrotech* □

Worked on novel problems related to the Agro-industry with Deep Learning as well as traditional computer vision methods with OpenCV.

Assisted and worked with:

- Research and Patent team in ongoing research.
- Backend team with the development of API and assure that API generates accurate results.
- Hiring team with the initial screening of the candidates for intern roles.

Aug 2021 – present California, USA

#### Mentor

DeepLearning.AI ☑

Helped candidates enrolled in specific Coursera courses by solving their doubts, sharing learning material, and career advices.

Mar 2021 – Jun 2021 Pune, India

# **Data Analyst Intern**

Analytics Domain □

Created a web application-based analysis tool that would leverage data from public APIs. Curated course content for Machine Learning and Deep Learning topics at the beginner and intermediate levels. With the produced courses and a variety of user-side features, developed a Learning Management System.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Jun 2021

# Genomics, High Performance Computing and Machine Learning

*UIJRT (United International Journal for Research & Technology)* 

This paper aims to explore in a very uncomplicated manner, what exactly is genomics, where does high performance computing and machine learning come into picture, current applications and discuss potential future scope.

#### Nov 2020 PCOcare PCOS Detection and Prediction using Machine Learning

Algorithms 2

Bioscience Biotechnology Research Communications

Using 5 Machine Learning Algorithms, this research attempts to provide a system that can aid in the early diagnosis and prediction of PCOS therapy based on an optimal and minimal set of parameters.

#### **AWARDS**

Nov 2020

# Best Paper Award

*International Conference on Intelligent Systems, Data Science and Computing*Best Research Paper Award in Machine Learning Track.

## **PROJECTS**

Oct 2020 - Nov 2020

# **PCOcare: PCOS Detection & Prediction using ML** ☑

Research Project

A system that can aid in the early identification and prediction of PCOS treatment is offered. There were several Machine Learning classifiers used. For feature engineering, the CHI square strategy is employed.

May 2021 - present

# Segmentation of Fire and Smoke in Nano-Satellite Imagery using Mask

R-CNN and Res-UNet

Research Project

Image Segmentation Algorithms such as Mask Region-Based Convolutional Neural Network (Mask R-CNN), UNet, and Deep Residual U-NET successfully separated natural objects such as clouds, snow, and rivers against smoke caused by a forest fire.

Jun 2021 – Jul 2021

# Loan Management System - Flask API

*Private Project* 

Simple loan management API made with FLASK as the backend and SQLite as the database. Token-based authentication, with Flask Blueprints for future scaling.

Jul 2021 – Jul 2021

## **Hardhat Detection: Dynamically Colored Bounding Boxes**

*Private Project* 

Detecting hardhats in an image/video/live stream and offering security approval based on the color of the hardhat.

# **CERTIFICATES**

• DeepLearning.AI TensorFlow Developer ☑

• TensorFlow: Advanced Techniques

• Generative Adversarial Networks (GANS) ☑

#### **REFERENCES**

**Dr. Kalpana Thakre**, *Professor*, Sinhgad College of Engineering, Pune kalpana\_sunil@yahoo.com, 9922411355

**Shilpa Sonawani**, *Associate Professor*, MIT World Peace University, Pune shilpa.sonawani@mitwpu.edu.in, 8698955002